<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Studio Ember</title><link>https://studioember.com/</link><description>Recent content on Studio Ember</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://studioember.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Support</title><link>https://studioember.com/billsio/support/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/billsio/support/</guid><description>Welcome to the Bills io FAQ. Here you will find an ever growing resource to assist in the use of the app. More content will be added as it is created.
Last updated: December 28, 2021
Philosophy Bills io is a finance planning app focused on two core concepts, “how much am I spending per month?” &amp;amp; “from which account am I paying each bill?”. Bills io was created to answer both of those questions.</description></item><item><title>Bills io, the origin</title><link>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/origin-bills-io/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/origin-bills-io/</guid><description>The idea for Bills io first originated in late 2019 as a way to put an end to my tireless switching of various productivity apps. Prior to creating this app, I used to use apps like Reminders, Todoist, Things, Numbers, etc. to try and create a system for remembering which bills to pay and when. In this process, I was able to create a system, but no app fit that payment flow.</description></item><item><title>Changelog &amp; Updates</title><link>https://studioember.com/billsio/changelog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/billsio/changelog/</guid><description>Ongoing list of updates and changes to Bills io. If you have a feature request or see a bug, please report it to our GitHub Issue Board.
Create a new bug or feature request
v2.1.1 - Saying hi to macOS Features 🪟 Bills io is now written for the Mac with native macOS window management 📝 Payment note copying 🧑‍💻 Markdown support in Payment notes 🧮 Testing calculated costs for bills without a specific amount 👆 New swipe actions throughout the app 🗑 Archived bills are now more distinguished from active bills 💸 Future payments now have a dedicated overview feature v2.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>https://studioember.com/billsio/privacy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/billsio/privacy/</guid><description>Last updatedOctober 5, 2021
Studio Ember Studio Ember LLC is a independently owned business founded by Nathan Grey. This website and all of its information are owned by the aforementioned company. Signing up for this website grants Studio Ember the permission to send occassional newsletter updates. This website is hosted by Ghost and their privacy policy.
If you have any questions or concerns, please reach out to contact@studioember.com
Bills io Studio Ember LLC is the organized company behind Bills io.</description></item><item><title>Features</title><link>https://studioember.com/billsio/features/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/billsio/features/</guid><description>Payment Tracking Track and record payments with note tracking. Save confirmation code, reference numbers, etc.
Encrypted, Private, and Secure No trackers, analytics, or linking bank accounts. Your data is yours, stored and accessed from iCloud.
Fully Functioning Free Tie Tracking expenses shouldn&amp;rsquo;t cost money. The free tier is fully capable of managing a basic budget.
Set &amp;amp; Remember Easily track and plan your recurring bills. Come back later when you need to check their status.</description></item><item><title>April 21, 2021 Apple Event</title><link>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/april-2021-event-recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/april-2021-event-recap/</guid><description>This should be a quick recap of Apple&amp;rsquo;s April event. Overall, it was a typical hardware announcement event. I was impressed with how many colors they added to the new iMac. The interesting fact that the M1 processor remained the M1 and didn&amp;rsquo;t increment yet for the iMac means we will be waiting for M2 with the Pro devices.
Speaking of Pro, the iPad Pro update was simultaneously bland yet the most interesting read after the fact.</description></item><item><title>Public SSH Keys Page</title><link>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/public-ssh-keys/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/public-ssh-keys/</guid><description>tldr;
curl https://github.com/YOUR_GITHUB_USERNAME.keys &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $HOME/.ssh/authorized_keys When working on server or connecting to remote hosts, having ssh access is vital. It took me by surprise that GitHub and GitLab both host these pages for public ssh keys. This makes it super easy to access for times when you cannot paste into a remote server.
I also use this to add keys for co-workers or sending the above tldr; to a client to add my keys.</description></item><item><title>Creating this Blog via Hugo</title><link>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/new-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/new-blog/</guid><description>When starting a new project, picking the right frameworks and stack can make further development a lot more pleasant for your future self. Thinking about how I wanted to develop this blog was not an easy task. My first instinct was to purchase a monthly subscription to Ghost Blog. At the time, the lowest subscription was about $30 / month billed annually. For a casual blog with no revenue, this was way too expensive.</description></item><item><title>Welcome</title><link>https://studioember.com/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/posts/welcome/</guid><description>Thanks for visiting StudioEmber. My name is Nathan Grey and I am a developer at InnovoEdge specializing in all things containers and Kubernetes. In my free time, I develop Bills io, an entirely SwiftUI personal finance application for iPhone, iPad, and macOS.
This blog will focus primarily in my adventures in containerization, orchestration, SwiftUI, productivity, apps, development environments, general computer use, and other areas of life that interest me. Be sure to follow along with the tags that interest you.</description></item><item><title>Join the Beta</title><link>https://studioember.com/billsio/beta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/billsio/beta/</guid><description>Ongoing list of updates and changes to Bills io. If you have a feature request or see a bug, please report it to our GitHub Issue Board.
Create a new bug or feature request:
If you have a request / bug, please use GitHub - New Issue
TestFlight Information Join the public TestFlight
macOS now has the TestFlight App in the App Store and macOS beta builds will be submitted there.</description></item><item><title>Terms of Service</title><link>https://studioember.com/billsio/termsofservice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/billsio/termsofservice/</guid><description>Last Updated December 27, 2020
These terms of service (&amp;ldquo;Terms&amp;rdquo;) apply to your access and use of all Studio Ember LLC apps and services, including iOS apps and web services (the &amp;ldquo;Service&amp;rdquo;). Please read them carefully.
Accepting these Terms If you access or use the Service, it means you agree to be bound by all of the terms below. So, before you use the Service, please read all of the terms.</description></item></channel></rss>