<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on ðŸ”¥ Studio Ember</title><link>https://studioember.com/posts/</link><description>ðŸ”¥ Studio Ember (Posts)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://studioember.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>April 21, 2021 Apple Event</title><link>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/april-2021-event-recap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/april-2021-event-recap/</guid><description>&lt;p>This should be a quick recap of Apple&amp;rsquo;s April event. Overall, it was a typical hardware announcement event. I was impressed with how many colors they added to the new iMac. The interesting fact that the M1 processor remained the M1 and didn&amp;rsquo;t increment yet for the iMac means we will be waiting for M2 with the Pro devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking of Pro, the iPad Pro update was simultaneously bland yet the most interesting read after the fact. Hardware-wise, it is the same look. Inside though, adding an M1 chip, Thunderbolt, AND up to 16gb of ram. This didn&amp;rsquo;t hit me at first, but in my opinion, WWDC is going to bring MAJOR iPadOS changes. Typically, Apple bumps iPad hardware in the spring and matches the OS in the summer. Everything is adding up for this year to bring some sort of new windows manager for external displays. These iPads are getting too powerful not to have more productivity options. At the time of writing, I would love to trade in a MacBook Air to get an iPad Pro with a caveat. It would have to either virtualize macOS and output it to a monitor while docked, or it would have to have a desktop like windows manager. I would wager on the latter, and I believe it will be coming as a preview for WWDC. This could really be a game-changing device for portability and productivity. Fingers crossed on this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, the other minor things that were announced were AirTags and Apple TV. AirTags, simple, find your stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s a tile. The Apple TV also got nice improvements, processor bump, and a new remote. All good updates, took too long, but good. Out of all the announcements, this is what I will be picking up.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Public SSH Keys Page</title><link>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/public-ssh-keys/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/public-ssh-keys/</guid><description>&lt;p>tldr;&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">curl https://github.com/YOUR_GITHUB_USERNAME.keys &amp;gt;&amp;gt; $HOME/.ssh/authorized_keys
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>When working on server or connecting to remote hosts, having ssh access is vital. It took me by surprise that GitHub and GitLab both host these pages for public ssh keys. This makes it super easy to access for times when you cannot paste into a remote server.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also use this to add keys for co-workers or sending the above tldr; to a client to add my keys. It is super easy to remember, or type in. Try it out with scripts or easy to send commands for clients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Below are the public address format for both GitHub and GitLab.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>GitHub:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">https://github.com/GITHUB_USERNAME.key
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>GitLab:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">https://gitlab.com/GITLAB_USERNAME.key
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Hope this helps someone save time for transferring public keys around the web!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Creating this Blog via Hugo</title><link>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/new-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/posts/blog/new-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p>When starting a new project, picking the right frameworks and stack can make further development a lot more pleasant for your future self. Thinking about how I wanted to develop this blog was not an easy task. My first instinct was to purchase a monthly subscription to &lt;a href="https://ghost.org">Ghost Blog&lt;/a>. At the time, the lowest subscription was about $30 / month billed annually. For a casual blog with no revenue, this was way too expensive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started to branch out and look at alternatives or self hosting. Diving deeper about self hosting, preserving content, and managing backups just seemed like extra work for little return. I am a single developer just wanting to publish some articles in Markdown when the mood strikes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Free is an adequate price.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I knew GitHub Pages were a possibility, but really I didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy their default offering, &lt;a href="https://jekyllrb.com">jekyll&lt;/a>. It seemed a bit too messy with the rigid config and ruby base. There is nothing wrong with ruby, just something I never worked with. For the last few years, GoLang has been my main language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I found &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-hugo">Why Hugo&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a> offered something very compelling, a theme-able, structured, static, markdown based website creator. This along with GitHub actions and pages, a quick and backed up blog could be hosted for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="stack">Stack&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You can read more about the content structure &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/organization/">here&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;m also still learning&amp;hellip; Basically the stack is as follows:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback"> â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”
â”‚ Project Files â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
â”‚
â–¼
â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”
â”‚ Git (Backup) â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
â”‚
â–¼
â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”
â”‚ GitHub Action â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
â”‚
â–¼
â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”
â”‚ GitHub Pages â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
â”‚
â–¼
â”Œâ”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”
â”‚ Website :) â”‚
â””â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”€â”˜
created with MonoDraw &amp;lt;3
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This stack gives a powerful yet stress free blogging platform. Is it a bit technical? Sure, but the core concept of taking a markdown file and publishing it to a platform you control is worth it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can view the &lt;a href="https://github.com/studioember/website">source code&lt;/a> to see how this site is laid out. Keep in mind that the root of the project is not the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a> source. I placed everything in &lt;code>/site&lt;/code> to leave room for CI/CD scripts in the root.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-to">How To&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>First &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/">install Hugo&lt;/a> using whichever platform that is appropriate. A simple &lt;code>brew install hugo&lt;/code> on macOS did the trick for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next, generate a new project by using &lt;code>hugo new site example&lt;/code>. This will generate a base site with no content. At this point you can &lt;code>cd example&lt;/code> and run &lt;code>hugo server&lt;/code> to see your site at &lt;a href="http://localhost:1313">localhost:1313&lt;/a>. It will be blank.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After that, browse and find a theme you like to get started. &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a> offers a bunch &lt;a href="https://themes.gohugo.io">available here&lt;/a>. When you find a theme, just follow the theme&amp;rsquo;s README to install.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For this site, I used &lt;a href="https://github.com/mitrichius/hugo-theme-anubis">anubis&lt;/a>. The installation was pretty standard &lt;a href="https://github.com/mitrichius/hugo-theme-anubis#installation">here&lt;/a>. You can use git submodules, or simply download and extract the theme in the &lt;code>themes/&lt;/code> directory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, add a markdown file in &lt;code>content/&lt;/code> and configure you &lt;code>config.yaml|.toml|.json&lt;/code> file. This did get me, yes the config file can be in 3 different formats, all are valid. Just pay attention you are not inserting &lt;code>TOML&lt;/code> into a &lt;code>YAML&lt;/code> config. Your site should auto refresh at &lt;a href="http://localhost:1313">localhost:1313&lt;/a> now.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hosting">Hosting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A lot of this was taken care of with &lt;a href="https://github.com/marketplace/actions/hugo-setup">this Hugo GitHub Pages Action&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml">&lt;span style="color:#6272a4"># .github/workflows/gh-pages.yml&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">name&lt;/span>: github pages
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">on&lt;/span>:
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">push&lt;/span>:
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">branches&lt;/span>:
- main &lt;span style="color:#6272a4"># Set a branch to deploy&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">jobs&lt;/span>:
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">deploy&lt;/span>:
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">runs-on&lt;/span>: ubuntu-18.04
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">steps&lt;/span>:
- &lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">uses&lt;/span>: actions/checkout@v2
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">with&lt;/span>:
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">submodules&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">true&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#6272a4"># Fetch Hugo themes (true OR recursive)&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">fetch-depth&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#bd93f9">0&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#6272a4"># Fetch all history for .GitInfo and .Lastmod&lt;/span>
- &lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">name&lt;/span>: Setup Hugo
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">uses&lt;/span>: peaceiris/actions-hugo@v2
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">with&lt;/span>:
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">hugo-version&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#f1fa8c">&amp;#39;latest&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="color:#6272a4"># extended: true&lt;/span>
- &lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">name&lt;/span>: Build
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">run&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#f1fa8c">&amp;#34;hugo -s ./site/ --minify&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#6272a4"># Using ./site here&lt;/span>
- &lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">name&lt;/span>: Deploy
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">uses&lt;/span>: peaceiris/actions-gh-pages@v3
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">with&lt;/span>:
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">github_token&lt;/span>: ${{ secrets.GITHUB_TOKEN }}
&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">publish_dir&lt;/span>: &lt;span style="color:#f1fa8c">&amp;#34;./site/public&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#6272a4"># Using ./site here&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>This will go through and generate a new branch called &lt;code>gh-pages&lt;/code> with all of the static website content in it. I was a bit confused on why this happened, but apparently GitHub does not have artifacts like GitLab so a new branch is necessary for hosting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Configure your &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/github/working-with-github-pages/configuring-a-publishing-source-for-your-github-pages-site">GitHub Pages&lt;/a> with the correct branch, in this case &lt;code>gh-pages&lt;/code>, and you are all set for a &lt;code>$USERNAME.github.io page&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Setting up a custom domain is a bit more work, but &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/github/working-with-github-pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site">GitHub&amp;rsquo;s Documentation&lt;/a> provides some insight.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This was a quick way to get up and running with a blog that is fully version controlled and hosted for free. Hopefully, this helps shed some light on some initial issues you have getting hosting all set up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cheers ðŸ»&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Nathan Grey&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome</title><link>https://studioember.com/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://studioember.com/posts/welcome/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thanks for visiting &lt;a href="https://studioember.com">StudioEmber&lt;/a>. My name is &lt;a href="https://github.com/overtfuture">Nathan Grey&lt;/a> and I am a developer at &lt;a href="https://innovoedge.com">InnovoEdge&lt;/a> specializing in all things &lt;a href="https://www.docker.com/resources/what-container">containers&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io">Kubernetes&lt;/a>. In my free time, I develop &lt;a href="https://billsio.app">Bills io&lt;/a>, an entirely &lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/xcode/swiftui/">SwiftUI&lt;/a> personal finance application for iPhone, iPad, and macOS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This blog will focus primarily in my adventures in containerization, orchestration, SwiftUI, productivity, apps, development environments, general computer use, and other areas of life that interest me. Be sure to follow along with the tags that interest you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anything categorized under &lt;a href="https://studioember.com/categories/tutorials/">tutorials&lt;/a> will rely heavily on code snippets, images, videos, and breakdowns to illustrate the concepts. The first guide in &lt;a href="https://studioember.com/categories/tutorials/">tutorials&lt;/a> will focus on beginning this blog from scratch and taking you through every step for deploying a containerized blog with &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Be sure to come back later for new content and recommendations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Glad you decided to stop by ðŸ˜€&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>